{"Question":"Solve this system of equations: {4x + 2y = 0, -4x -9y = -28}","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":3,"Answer":"x = -2, y = 4","Source":"INTERMEDIATE ALGEBRA","Symbolic Form":"[[4*x + 2*y, -4*x -9*y + 28, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"No"}
{"Question":"Solve this system of equations: {-7x + 5y = -8, -3x -3y = 12}","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":3,"Answer":"x = -1, y = -3","Source":"INTERMEDIATE ALGEBRA","Symbolic Form":"[[-7*x + 5*y + 8, -3*x -3*y - 12, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"No"}
{"Question":"Solve this system of equations: {y = 2x - 3, y = -2x + 9}","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":3,"Answer":"x = 3, y = 3","Source":"INTERMEDIATE ALGEBRA","Symbolic Form":"[[y - 2*x + 3, y + 2*x - 9, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"No"}
{"Question":"Solve this system of equations: {-8x + 2y = -6, -2x + 3y = 11}","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":3,"Answer":"x = 2, y = 5","Source":"INTERMEDIATE ALGEBRA","Symbolic Form":"[[-8*x + 2*y + 6, -2*x + 3*y - 11, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"No"}
{"Question":"Solve this system of equations: {10x + 6y = 24, -6x + y = 4}","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":3,"Answer":"x = 0, y = 4","Source":"INTERMEDIATE ALGEBRA","Symbolic Form":"[[10*x + 6*y - 24, -6*x + y - 4, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"No"}
{"Question":"A boy has $ 2.25 in nickels and dimes. If there are twice as many dimes as nickels, how many of each kind of coin does he have?","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":3,"Answer":"x = 9, y = 18","Source":"INTERMEDIATE ALGEBRA","Symbolic Form":"[[0.05*x + 0.10*y - 2.25, y - 2*x, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"The total number of calories in 2 hot dogs and 3 cups of cottage cheese is 960 calories. The total number of calories in 5 hot dogs and 2 cups of cottage cheese is 1,190 calories. How many calories are in a hot dog? How many calories are in a cup of cottage cheese?","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":3,"Answer":"x = 150, y = 220","Source":"Contemporary Mathematics","Symbolic Form":"[[2*x + 3*y - 960, 5*x + 2*y - 1190, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"A piggy bank contains nickels and dimes. The number of dimes is ten less than twice the number of nickels. The total value of all the coins is $ 2.75. Find the number of each type of coin in the piggy bank.","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":3,"Answer":"x = 15, y = 20","Source":"INTERMEDIATE ALGEBRA","Symbolic Form":"[[0.05*x + 0.10*y - 2.75, y - 2*x + 10, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"June needs 48 gallons of punch for a party and has two different coolers to carry it in. The bigger cooler is five times as large as the smaller cooler. How many gallons can each cooler hold?","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":3,"Answer":"x = 0.4, y = 0.3","Source":"Contemporary Mathematics","Symbolic Form":"[[4*x + 5*y - 3.10, 4*x + 6*y - 3.40, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"Jackie has been offered positions by two cable companies. The first company pays a salary of $14,000 plus a commission of $100 for each cable package sold. The second pays a salary of $20,000 plus a commission of $25 for each cable package sold. How many cable packages would need to be sold to make the total pay the same?","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":4,"Answer":"x = 80","Source":"Contemporary Mathematics","Symbolic Form":"[[14000 + 100*x - y, 20000 + 25*x - y, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"The sum of two number is 30. One number is 4 less than the other. Find the numbers.","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":3,"Answer":"x=13, y=17","Source":null,"Symbolic Form":"[[x + y - 30, x - y - 4, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"The sum of two numbers is 45. Their difference is 89. Find the numbers.","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":3,"Answer":"x=22,y=-67","Source":null,"Symbolic Form":"[[x + y - 45, x - y - 89, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"The difference of two complementary angles is 17 degrees. Find the measures of the angles.","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":3,"Answer":"x=53.5,y=36.5","Source":null,"Symbolic Form":"[[x + y - 90, x - y - 17, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"The perimeter of a toddler play area is 100 feet. The length is ten more than three times the width. Find the length and width of the play area.","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":3,"Answer":"x=10,y=40","Source":null,"Symbolic Form":"[[2*x + 2*y - 100, x - 3*y - 10, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"A river cruise boat sailed 80 miles down the Mississippi River for four hours. It took five hours to return. Find the rate of the cruise boat in still water and the rate of the current.","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":3,"Answer":"x=18,y=2","Source":null,"Symbolic Form":"[[x + y - 80\/4, x - y - 80\/5, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"A small jet can fly 1435 miles in 5 hours with a tailwind but only 1,215 miles in 5 hours into a headwind. Find the speed of the jet in still air and the speed of the wind.","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":3,"Answer":"x=265,y=22","Source":null,"Symbolic Form":"[[x + y - 1435\/5, x - y - 1215\/5, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"Tickets for the Cirque du Soleil show are $70 for adults and $50 for children. One evening performance had a total of 300 tickets sold and the receipts totaled $17,200. How many adult and how many child tickets were sold?","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":4,"Answer":"x=110,y=190","Source":null,"Symbolic Form":"[[70*x + 50*y - 17200, x + y - 300, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"Joseph would like to make twelve pounds of a coffee blend at a cost of $6 per pound. He blends Ground Chicory at $5 a pound with Jamaican Blue Mountain at $9 per pound. How much of each type of coffee should he use?","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":4,"Answer":"x=9,y=3","Source":null,"Symbolic Form":"[[x + y - 12, 5*x + 9*y - 6*12, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"A cashier has 54 bills, all of which are $10 or $20 bills. The total value of the money is $910. How many of each type of bill does the cashier have?","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":4,"Answer":"x=17,y=37","Source":null,"Symbolic Form":"[[x + y - 54, 10*x + 20*y - 910, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"Lucinda had a pocketful of dimes and quarters with a value of  $6.20. The number of dimes is eighteen more than three times the number of quarters. How many dimes and how many quarters does Lucinda have?","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":4,"Answer":"x=42,y=8","Source":null,"Symbolic Form":"[[0.10*x + 0.25*y - 6.20, x - 3*y - 18, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"Tickets for a Minnesota Twins baseball game are $69 for Main Level seats and $39 for Terrace Level seats. A group of sixteen friends went to the game and spent a total of $804 for the tickets. How many of Main Level and how many Terrace Level tickets did they buy?","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":4,"Answer":"x=6,y=10","Source":null,"Symbolic Form":"[[x + y - 16, 69*x + 39*y - 804, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"A 90% antifreeze solution is to be mixed with a 75% antifreeze solution to get 360 liters of an 85% solution. How many liters of the 90% and how many liters of the 75% solutions will be used?","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":5,"Answer":"x=240,y=120","Source":null,"Symbolic Form":"[[x + y - 360, 0.90*x + 0.75*y - 306, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"Mark wants to invest $10,000 to pay for his daughter's wedding next year. He will invest some of the money in a short term CD that pays 12% interest and the rest in a money market savings account that pays 5% interest. How much should he invest at each rate if he wants to earn $1095 in interest in one year?","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":5,"Answer":"x=8500,y=1500","Source":null,"Symbolic Form":"[[x+y-10000,0.12*x+0.05*y-1095,x,y,solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
{"Question":"A business has two loans totaling $85,000. One loan has a rate of 6% and the other has a rate of 4.5% This year, the business expects to pay $4,650 in interest on the two loans. How much is each loan?","Type":"Systems of Linear Equations","Level":5,"Answer":"x=55000,y=30000","Source":null,"Symbolic Form":"[[x + y - 85000, 0.06*x + 0.045*y - 4650, x, y, solve]]","Word Problem":"Yes"}
